{
  "year5Ques": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "A mouse can do the following except _____.",
      "options": ["double click", "save information inside the mouse", "left and right click", "drag or move object from one place to another"],
      "answer": "save information inside the mouse"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Laptop, desktop, notebook, and pocket size computers are examples of _____.",
      "options": ["super computers", "mainframe computers", "omega computers", "micro or personal computers"],
      "answer": "micro or personal computers"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "One of the computer cables is called _____.",
      "options": ["battery cable", "power cable", "power socket", "power switch"],
      "answer": "power cable"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "These are electronics devices except a _______.",
      "options": ["television set", "cupboard", "radio", "computer"],
      "answer": "cupboard"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "One of these cannot be used to solve arithmetic problems:",
      "options": ["calculator", "computer", "shutters", "mobile phone"],
      "answer": "shutters"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "After processing, a computer result is the _____.",
      "options": ["output", "input", "control unit", "copies"],
      "answer": "output"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "_____ is the founder of Microsoft.",
      "options": ["Professor Wole Soyinka", "Bill Graham", "William Henry", "Bill Gates"],
      "answer": "Bill Gates"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "To insert spaces between words while typing we use _______.",
      "options": ["Caps lock key", "space bar", "back space key", "shift key"],
      "answer": "space bar"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The mouse can move smoothly because it has _____.",
      "options": ["two small tyres", "two small chains", "a moveable ball", "a special magnet"],
      "answer": "a moveable ball"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "The action of pressing the mouse to carry out a specific command is called ____. ",
      "options": ["command tuning", "clicking", "downloading", "pointing"],
      "answer": "clicking"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "The methods of booting a computer are _____.",
      "options": ["wet, dry, and rain booting", "cold booting, and warm booting", "hot, dry, and warm booting", "wet, warm, hot, and dry booting"],
      "answer": "cold booting, and warm booting"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Information in raw or unorganized form such as alphabet, numbers or symbols that represent ideas or objects is called _____.",
      "options": ["alphanumeric", "output", "data", "input"],
      "answer": "data"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "A piece of information that can be seen and heard is called _____.",
      "options": ["reality", "televised information", "audio", "audiovisual"],
      "answer": "audiovisual"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "The term used to describe the process of closing all software programs in preparation to turn off is called _____.",
      "options": ["computerâ€™s power", "close up", "turn off", "shut down"],
      "answer": "shut down"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "There are _____ methods in booting a computer.",
      "options": ["5", "4", "3", "2"],
      "answer": "2"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "Data that are written in letters A to Z are called _____.",
      "options": ["alphanumeric data", "numeric data", "alphabetic data", "lettered data"],
      "answer": "alphabetic data"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "______ is the arrangement of data into meaningful and useful information.",
      "options": ["Data processing", "Information management", "Computerization", "Softwaring"],
      "answer": "Data processing"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "What a computer can process is called _____.",
      "options": ["work", "output", "application", "Input"],
      "answer": "Input"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "The part of the computer which works like the human eye is called the _____.",
      "options": ["hard disk", "monitor", "scanner", "mouse"],
      "answer": "monitor"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following describes a correct usage of computer?",
      "options": ["Cyberbullying", "Scamming", "Spamming", "Storing information"],
      "answer": "Storing information"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "______________ is a place where all deleted files and documents are kept?",
      "options": ["recycle bin", "dustbin", "waste bin", "trash bin"],
      "answer": "recycle bin"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "When the mouse button is pressed twice quickly and released, it's known as ____________.",
      "options": ["Dragging", "Double clicking", "Clicking", "Flapping"],
      "answer": "Double clicking"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "The following are software used for typing except _____________.",
      "options": ["Word pad", "Microsoft Word", "Photoshop", "Microsoft Excel"],
      "answer": "Photoshop"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "Before carrying out any command on a text, you must first ___________.",
      "options": ["Highlight", "Drag", "Permission", "Click"],
      "answer": "Highlight"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "The term O.S means _________.",
      "options": ["Open statement", "Operating system", "Operating state", "Open Sentence"],
      "answer": "Operating system"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "Development of computer from one period to another is called _______.",
      "options": ["Computer age", "Computer generation", "Computer stage", "Computer development"],
      "answer": "Computer generation"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "A computer system which supplies other remote computers with processed information is called ___________.",
      "options": ["Client", "Server", "Processor", "Supplier"],
      "answer": "Server"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "Microsoft Word is primarily used for _________.",
      "options": ["Calculation", "Typing", "Drawing", "Painting"],
      "answer": "Typing"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "When a text is moved from one document to another, it is called __________.",
      "options": ["Copy and paste", "Cut and paste", "Delete", "Move and paste"],
      "answer": "Cut and paste"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "People who write instructions for computers to solve problems are called ________.",
      "options": ["Producer", "Programmer", "Writer", "Processor"],
      "answer": "Programmer"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "question": "A program installed in a computer for typing is called _________.",
      "options": ["E-mail", "Data", "Word processor", "Software"],
      "answer": "Word processor"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "question": "One of these is not considered as a drawing package:",
      "options": ["Ms-Word", "Paint Artist", "Corel draw", "Paint environment"],
      "answer": "Ms-Word"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "question": "The acronym C.P.U. means _________.",
      "options": ["Computer Processing Unit", "Central Programming Unit", "Central Processing Unit", "Center Processing Unit"],
      "answer": "Central Processing Unit"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "question": "A place on the internet where computer users can find necessary information is called ___________.",
      "options": ["Software", "Web cam", "Website", "Webster"],
      "answer": "Website"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "question": "For you to write on the computer, you need a ____________.",
      "options": ["Marker", "Joystick", "Keyboard", "Data"],
      "answer": "Keyboard"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "question": "The longest key on the keyboard is _________.",
      "options": ["Space bar key", "Enter key", "Backspace key", "Cap lock key"],
      "answer": "Space bar key"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "question": "If Ctrl + A means select all text, then Ctrl + B means .__",
      "options": ["Refresh the current program", "Save current document file", "Change selected text to be bold", "Print all text"],
      "answer": "Change selected text to be bold"
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "question": "\"GIGO\" is a computer term that means _____________.",
      "options": ["Go in, go out", "Get in, get out", "Garbage in, garbage out", "Barge in, barge out"],
      "answer": "Garbage in, garbage out"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "question": "Information from a computer that has been printed on paper is called ____________.",
      "options": ["Computer print", "Soft copy", "Hard copy", "Master copy"],
      "answer": "Hard copy"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "question": "When you want to make a document, you are said to _______ a document.",
      "options": ["Make", "Keep", "Create", "Design"],
      "answer": "Create"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "question": "Ctrl + X means _______________.",
      "options": ["Cut selected item", "Copy selected item", "Save the current document file", "Cut and paste selected item"],
      "answer": "Cut selected item"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "question": "After using the computer, the next thing to do is_____________.",
      "options": ["Short down", "Shut up", "Shut down", "Close down"],
      "answer": "Shut down"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "question": "What is E-mail?",
      "options": ["Electronic mail", "Electrical mail", "Every mail", "Electronic mall"],
      "answer": "Electronic mail"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "question": "Ctrl + V means _______________.",
      "options": ["Save", "Copy", "Paste", "Delete"],
      "answer": "Paste"
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "question": "An input device that looks like the gear selector of a car used for playing a computer game is called ____________.",
      "options": ["Light pen", "Special pen", "Joystick", "Pen pad"],
      "answer": "Joystick"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "question": "The word YEAR FIVE will be underlined if I press ___________",
      "options": ["Ctrl + N", "Ctrl + W", "Ctrl + U", "Ctrl + P"],
      "answer": "Ctrl + U"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "question": "If a red wavy line is shown in MS word it means _____________",
      "options": ["Spelling error", "Danger", "Correction", "Red alert"],
      "answer": "Spelling error"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "question": "Data can be defined as a __________.",
      "options": ["raw unprocessed facts", "Processed facts", "sources of information", "manipulated information"],
      "answer": "raw unprocessed facts"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "question": "The shading of objects after drawing is to make the work look _________.",
      "options": ["flat", "Attractive", "Beautiful", "Colourful"],
      "answer": "Attractive"
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "question": "Which of the following can be called the brain of computer?",
      "options": ["ROM", "CPU", "RAM", "UPS"],
      "answer": "CPU"
    },
    {
      "id": 51,
      "question": "What does â€˜Fâ€™ means on the F1, F2, F3, etc., in the computer keyboard?",
      "options": ["Format", "Function", "File", "Find"],
      "answer": "Function"
    },
    {
      "id": 52,
      "question": "Which is not a computer Input device?",
      "options": ["Web camera", "Printer", "Keyboard", "Mouse"],
      "answer": "Printer"
    },
    {
      "id": 53,
      "question": "Choose the two kinds of storage devices used by a computer.",
      "options": ["Flash drive and Hard drive", "Motherboard and Monitor", "Scanner and Keyboard", "Speaker and Microphone"],
      "answer": "Flash drive and Hard drive"
    },
    {
      "id": 54,
      "question": "A computer language used for programming is:",
      "options": ["English Language", "French", "Java", "Windows"],
      "answer": "Java"
    },
    {
      "id": 55,
      "question": "What is the physical part of a computer called?",
      "options": ["System unit", "Program", "Hardware", "Software"],
      "answer": "Hardware"
    },
    {
      "id": 56,
      "question": "Base 2 is called _____.",
      "options": ["binary", "denary", "octave", "basic base"],
      "answer": "binary"
    },
    {
      "id": 57,
      "question": "avaacademy@yahoo.com is a/an ______.",
      "options": ["Official address", "Email address", "Computer address", "Website address"],
      "answer": "Email address"
    },
    {
      "id": 58,
      "question": "One of these is not a characteristic of a computer system?",
      "options": ["Speed", "Accuracy", "Consistency", "Problematic"],
      "answer": "Problematic"
    },
    {
      "id": 59,
      "question": "An example of a removable storage device is _____.",
      "options": ["system unit", "visual display unit", "flash drive", "motherboard"],
      "answer": "flash drive"
    },
    {
      "id": 60,
      "question": "The computer and robots imitate man through their _____.",
      "options": ["natural intelligence", "superior intelligence", "advanced intelligence", "artificial intelligence"],
      "answer": "artificial intelligence"
    }
  ]
}
